A register of the Aleksandr Il'ich Ginzburg Papers, 1921-2007
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1967-2005.; 2 boxes (Box 4-5)
  - Russkaia mysl' correspondence of Aleksandr and Arina Ginzburg, 1980-1999 and undated (Folder 5: 4-9)
    - NaĬman, AnatoliĬ, 1996 Nekrasov, Viktor Platonovich, photocopy, 1982 Orlova, Raisa, 1982. Parnis, Aleksandr, 1996 Pazhitnov, Leonid, 1980s Plankett, Patrice de, 1995 PribylovskiĬ, Vladimir, after 1989. Reddaway, Peter, 1982 Ross, Ed, 1995 Rostin, Petr (pseudonym), 1982 Ryzhov, IuriĬ, 1992 (Folder 5: 8)
      Includes cover letter from GrigoriĬ Tochkin
      See box 5, folder 9, for letter from Boris Suvarin
    - San, D. de (UNESCO), 1997 Shaposhnikov, EvgeniĬ Ivanovich (Aeroflot), 1996 ShteĬn, Eduard, 1982 Struve, Nikita (YMCA-PRESS), 1994 August 31 Superfin, Gabriel', 1999 Suvarin, Boris, 1982. Ulanovskaia, MaĬia 1987 VaĬl', Petr, and Aleksandr Genis, 1982 Vins, GeorgiĬ, 1981 Vins, Lidiia, 1982 Voronel', Nina, 1982 Voznesenskaia, IUliia, 1981-1982. Zaks, Boris, 1982 and undated Zernova, Ruth (Ruf'), 1985 ZholkovskiĬ, Aleksandr, 1985 (Folder 5: 9)
      Includes photocopies of Voznesenskaia's letters
      See also box 5, folder 8 for letter from Raisa Orlova
  - Collected correspondence, 1969-1997 (Folder 5: 10-)
    - Unidentified to Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna, 1984 Baltic republics appeal to governments of the Soviet Union, Federal Republic of Germany, and other countries, and to Kurt Waldheim, Secretary General of the UN, 1979 Daniel', IUliĬ, to Political Prisoners Aid Fund and Ginzburg's lawyer, 1969 and 1972 Galanskov, IUri, probably to Olga Timofeeva, 1971 Ivanov, Aleksandr, to the Stolypins, undated Kalnyn'sh, Viktor, to the Committee of State Security (KGB), 1978 Lupan, Viktor, to Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, 1997 Maksimov, Vladimir, to Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, 1990 Ptushkina, M., to Vladimir BukovskiĬ, 1996 Sapgir, Kira, to E. Averin (chief editor of the Knizhnoe obozrenie weekly), 1991. Sidorov, EvgeniĬ (minister of culture of the Russian Federation) to IuriĬ Luzhkov (mayor of Moscow), 1995 Trifonov, GrigoriĬ, to "Grant," 1987. Verrue, Robert, to the European Commission, 1984 (Folder 5: 10)
      Includes clipping from Knizhnoe obozrenie and a note from Liudmila Foster (Voice of America)
- Speeches and writings, 1985-2001 and undated., 5 folders (Folder 5: 11-13, 29: 5-6)
  Includes excerpts from Ginzburg's memoirs, transcripts of his essays, interviews and reviews, and an open letter.
  Arranged chronologically by title.
  - "Na dvore byl 1967 god,", undated. (Folder 5: 11)
    Excerpts from unfinished memoirs. Holograph. Includes Ginzburg's version of a new Russian anthem and background notes by Arina Ginzburg.
  - "Optimist–retsidivist po imeni Alik,", undated. (Folder 5: 11)
    Interview. Typescript with holograph corrections
  - "Tol'ko odin god — 1976: Dissidenty i svoboda sovesti,", undated. (Folder 5: 11)
    Excerpts from unfinished memoirs. Holograph
  - Interview by Raisa Orlova, 1985. (Folder 5: 12)
    Transcript, with cover letter from Orlova
  - Draft review of 1995 publications in Russian periodicals, 1995 or after. (Folder 5: 12)
    Holograph
  - "Bulat i postupok,", 1998 or 1999. (Folder 5: 12)
    Draft of paper presented at the First International Conference commemorating Bulat Okudzhava. Typescript
  - Interview by Annie Tchernychev for KUBABA magazine, 1999. (Folder 5: 12)
    Includes cover letter from A. Tchernychev
  - "Nikogda ne govori nikogda,", 2000. (Folder 5: 12)
    Comments regarding the book Shcharansky bez maski, by IUliĬ Nudel'man (Be ėr-Sheva: Izd-vo "Negev-press," 1999)
  - "Pamiati glasnosti," open letter in support of free press in Russia, 2000. (Folder 5: 13)
    Original and copies. Includes background notes by Arina Ginzburg
  - "Alik Ginzburg — dedushka russkogo dissidentstva,", 2001. (Folder 5: 13)
    Interview by Igor' Shevelev for Moscow News. Typescript
  - Open letter in support of NTV (National Russian Television), 2001 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Moscow News clipping accompanying interview "Alik Ginzburg — dedushka russkogo dissidentstva,", 2001 (Folder 30: 5)
  - "Pravozashchitnika Aleksandra Giznburga ne puskaiut v Rossiiu,", 2001. (Folder 30: 5)
    Interview by DmitriĬ Volchek for Radio Liberty. Includes transcript on floppy disk and a copy of the transcript printed out by the Hoover Archives
  - "Sakharov — on vypolnil svoiu missiiu," Izvestiia, 21 May 2001 (Folder 30: 6)
- Writings by others, 1960-2004.; 1 box (Folder 5: 14-18, 6: 1-8)
  Includes published and unpublished works.
  Arranged alphabetically by author or title.
  - Ginzburg, Arina, paper presented at the Storie di uomini giusti nel Gulag international symposium in Milan, Italy, 2004 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Gokhman, Mikhail, "C'est un ordre — il faut survivre: La situation politique à Moscou" in Pensée russe, no. 4157, 16 December 1997 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Gorbanevskaia, Natal'ia, 1965-1970 (Folder 5: 15)
    - Poetry, 1967-1970. (Folder 5: 15)
      Typescript
    - PoteriannyĬ raĬ, 1965. (Folder 5: 15)
      Typescript, with inscription by the author to Ginzburg
  - Il'ina, Vera (wife of philosopher Vladimir Il'in), interview, undated. Transcript Kotova, Tat'iana (pseudonym), poetry, 1986-1988 Kovalev, SergeĬ, interview by Ginzburg for the "Gorizontal'" newspaper project, 2001. (Folder 5: 16)
  - Litvinova (IAsinovskaia), Flora, recollections, undated. Makhonin, Filip, "O moikh vstrechakh s Viktorom Nekrasovym," 26 September 1997. (Folder 5: 17)
    Includes photographs depicting Nekrasov and Makhonin and illustrations to Nekrasov's book V okopakh Stalingrada
  - Mel'nikova, Tat'iana, "Tarusa — 101-i kilometr," undated. Michel, Françoise, "La dissidence soviétique, ferment de la société civile russe," 2001. (Folder 5: 18)
    Typescripts
  - "Pochemu i ia khristianin," sample of religious Samizdat, 1968. (Folder 6: 1)
    Bound typescript
  - Rasa, Maria A., Zeks, play, 1980-1982. (Folder 6: 2)
    Includes photograph and a letter from actor Oliver Stone
    Translated from Lithuanian. Typescript.
  - Rozanova (Siniavski), Maria, interview by Aleksandr Ginzburg, 2002. (Folder 6: 3)
    Typescript printed from floppy disk in ELECTRONIC DOCUMENTS, box 13
  - Sapgir, Kira, essays for the "Gorizontal'" newspaper project, undated. (Folder 6: 4)
  - Severianin, Igor, 1960s. (Folder 6: 5)
    Samizdat book of poems created by Ginzburg, in his handwriting
  - Skujenieks, Kurt, "Evridika," poem, undated. (Folder 6: 5)
    See unnumbered compact sound cassette in box 17, "IUliĬ Daniel' reading Knut Skujenieks poetry"
  - Vaissié, Cécile. "La parole contre les mythes: Les dissidents de Russie (1968-1987),", 1999. (Folder 6: 6)
    Dissertation summary, with cover letter
  - Vladimov, GeorgiĬ, "Igraiut, kak umeiut,", 1992. (Folder 6: 7)
    Typescript. Includes a letter from I. IlovaĬskaia to the author, 1992 March 6
  - ZaslavskiĬ, RitaliĬ, poetry, 1993-1997. (Folder 6: 8)
- Subject file, 1962-2002; undated.; 17 folders (Box 6: 9-18, 30: 7-8, 7: 1-5)
  Includes advertising material, clippings, certificates, portrait sketches, reports, and Solzhenitsyn Fund documents.
  - Advertising and related information, undated. (Folder 6: 9)
    Includes advertising materials of ITAR-TASS, Raritet 537, Literaturnaia gazeta, International Cultural Initiative Foundation, Demokraticheskaia programma FAR i TASIS
  - Aleksandr Ginzburg memoirs project, 986-1999. (Folder 6 :10, 30: 7)
    Includes clippings, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty publications
  - Assotsiatsiia razvitiia russkoi kul'tury, 1994. (Folder 6: 11)
    Includes registration certificate, printed statute, letterheads, notifications
  - Convention Collective Nationale de Travail des Journalistes, 1987 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Dissidents, 1966-2002 (Folder 6: 13, 30: 8)
    - General, 1966-2002 (Folder 6: 13, 30: 8)
      - Clippings, mostly photocopies from Russkaia mysl', 1966-1997, bulk 1978-1981. (Folder 30: 8)
        Relates to the dissident movement in the Soviet Union
      - Clippings, 1989-1994 and 2002 (Folder 6: 13)
        Relates to polemics about Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn. Includes a letter from Aleksandr Daniel' to Russkaia mysl' and a clipping from Le Nouvel observateur
    - Gratitude Fund, 2000 IUrkevich, Igor', 1969. Indictment on charges of anti-Soviet activities Sidenko, Fedor, 1970. Release certificate (Folder 6: 13)
  - Dronnikov-Konovalov, NikolaĬ, 1998-2002. (Folder 6: 14-15)
    Five sets of portrait sketches depicting Ginzburg, Vladimir Maksimov, AndreĬ SiniavskiĬ, and Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn
  - Fond istoricheskikh issledovaniĬ imeni Mikhaila Gellera, printed statute, 2000. (Folder 6: 16)
  - Independent Lawyers, Inc., constituent agreement, 1993. (Folder 6: 17)
  - Memorial'nyi muzei zhertv politicheskikh repressiĬ i totalitarizma, 1994. (Folder 6: 18)
    Includes draft statute, report, and correspondence
  - National Endowment for Democracy, proposal preparation guidelines, undated. (Folder 7: 1)
  - Panorama, informatsionno-issledovatel'skiĬ tsentr, 1997. (Folder 7: 2)
    Includes questionnaire completed by Ginzburg
  - Solzhenitsyn Fund, 1962-1990. (Folder 7: 3)
    Includes financial documents and data relating to prosecuted fund members
  - Vorontsov-Vel'iaminov family, 2001. (Folder 7: 4)
    Documents relating to assistance rendered to them, with their letters
  - War in Chechnia, 1999-2000. (Folder 7: 5)
    Includes clippings from Russian and French press, open letters, appeals, minutes of meetings of the State Duma of the Russian Federation, "Putin-voina" postcard
- Printed matter, 1921-2001; bulk 1981-2001; 7 folders (Box 7: 6-12, 30: 9)
  Includes catalogs, programs, bulletins, newspaper and magazine issues.
  Arranged alphabetically by title, author, or type of material.
  - Advertising publications, 1981-1995 (Folder 7: 6-7)
    - Bulat Okudzhava concert in Paris program, 1981 Les thèmes éernels dans l'art contemporain des peintres de la Russie et des peintres russes de l'étranger exhibit catalog, 1995 MuzeĬ i obshchestvennyĬ tsentr imeni Andreia Sakharova, catalog, 1997. (Folder 7: 6)
    - Catalogs of Russian periodicals, 1994; 1995 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Pomoshch', Biulleten' VserrossiĬskogo komiteta pomoshchi golodaiushchim, 1991. (Folder 7: 8)
    Reprint of the 1921 bulletin published in London, with introductory essay by Mikhail Gel'man
  - Belaia vorona, no. 7(15), 1996. (Folder 7: 9)
    Gazeta russkikh belykh emigrantov i ikh potomkov v Bolgarii
  - Grani, magazine, no. 62, 1966. (Folder 7: 9)
    Contains documents from the AndreĬ SiniavskiĬ and IUliĬ Daniel' trial
  - Krasnaia zvezda, 1984. (Folder 7: 10)
    Forged newspaper published by Russian émigrés in Paris for distribution in Afghanistan
  - Lettre de Russie, no. 5, August 1993. (Folder 7: 10)
    Centre de Recherches Entreprises et Sociétés (en collaboration avec La Pensée russe)
  - Limonka, 2001. (Folder 7: 10)
    Special issue with open letter to Vladimir Putin from Eduard Savenko (Limonov)
  - Moskovskaia khartiia zhurnalistov, deklaratsiia, 1994. (Folder 7: 10)
  - Russkaia pravda, special issue no. 1(3), 1996. (Folder 7: 10)
    VserossiĬskaia gazeta natsional'no-osvoboditel'nogo dvizheniia. Published by AlekseĬ Dobrovol'skiĬ. Photocopy
  - Sintaksis, nos. 1-3, 1959-1960. (Folder 7: 11)
    Reprinted in Grani magazine. Photocopy
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, Arkhipelag Gulag (Paris: YMKA–Press), undated. (Folder 7: 12)
    Miniature reprint from the 1973 edition. Two volumes
  - Literaturnaia gazeta, no. 43, 27 October 1976 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Segodnia, no. 239, 22 October 1999 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, "Nash dukh sil'nee gnetushchego bytiia,"Argumenty i fakty, no. 4, 2001 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Vecherniaia Moskva, 20 September 2001 (Folder 30: 9)
- Russkaia Mysl' file, 1980s; 1991-1997; 5 boxes, 1 folder (Box 8: 1-17, 9: 1-12, 10: 1-12, 11: 1-8, 12: 1-8, 12, 30: 10)
  Includes advertising material, business agreements and proposals, correspondence, distribution and financial records, Moscow bureau file, office materials, and letters in support of the newspaper and other correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Advertising documents, 1993-1996. (Folder 8: 1-2, 30: 10)
    Includes catalog, sample advertisements, and advertising rates and provisions
  - Business agreements and proposals, 1993-1997 (Folder 8: 3-9)
    - Diagilev tsentr (Moscow association), 16 August 1993. (Folder 8: 3)
      Includes financial and advertising documents
    - Divin Joint Stock Company, 1993. (Folder 8: 4)
      Mostly business correspondence
    - Marium Publishers, 1993. (Folder 8: 5)
      Includes publishing agreement between Marium and Pressa agencies, letterhead, financial documents, and distribution agreements
    - Mediakom company, 1996-1997. (Folder 8: 6)
      Documents relating to publishing Russkaia mysl' in electronic format
    - MIK Publishers, 25 August 1996. (Folder 8: 7)
      Concerns distribution of Russkaia mysl' within the Russian Federation, CIS, and Baltic States
    - Referendum Foundation, 1995-1996. (Folder 8: 8)
      Includes agreement, correspondence, distribution lists, and financial documents
    - Russkaia galereia joint-stock association, 1995. Agreement regarding The Silver Age of the Russian Poetry exhibit Russkaia press sluzhba (agency), 1994. Draft agreement Proposals, 1993-1997 and undated (Folder 8: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s. (Folder 8: 10-11)
    Includes letters and documents related to controversy generated by the 1982 letter of Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn to President Ronald Reagan and to the establishment of the Moscow division of Russkaia mysl'
  - Distribution records, 1993-1995 (Folder 8: 12-17, 9: 1-3)
    - Lists of subscribers, 1994-1995 and undated (Folder 8: 12-17, 9: 1)
    - Orders from distributors, 1993 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Reviews and surveys, 1994-1995. (Folder 9: 2)
      Relates to availability and distribution of Russkaia mysl'
    - Subscription requests, 1995 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Financial records, 1992-1997 (Folder 9: 4-12, 10: 1-5)
    - Expenses, 1994-1997 and undated (Folder 9: 4-6)
      - Distribution, undated. (Folder 9: 4)
        Includes expenditure review
      - Postal and telephone, 1993-1997 (Folder 9: 5)
      - Printing, 1994-1995 (Folder 9: 6)
    - Honoraria, 1992-1997 (Folder 9: 7-12, 10 :1)
      - General, 1992-1997 (Folder 9: 7-10)
      - Moscow, 1994-1996. (Folder 9: 11-12, 10: 1)
        Includes invoices and acknowledgements
    - Invoices and bills, 1996 (Folder 10: 2)
    - Marium publisher's account, 1993 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Payment sheets and acknowledgements, 1996-1997 and undated (Folder 10: 4)
    - Revenues and expenditures, 1993-1996. (Folder 10: 5-6)
      Includes revenue and expenditure sheets and reports, invoices, and bills
  - Izdatel'skiĬ dom RM (Russkaia mysl') file, 1993-1994. (Folder 10: 7-8)
    Includes constituent agreement and statute
  - Moscow Bureau materials, 1992-1996 (Folder 10: 9-12)
    - Clippings, 1992-1994 (Folder 10: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Folder 10: 10)
    - Office establishment documents, 1991-1996. (Folder 10: 11-12)
      Includes apartment lease agreement, municipal and utility service file, travel documents, correspondence, and letterhead samples
  - Office reference materials, 1993-1997 and undated. (Folder 11: 1-5)
    Includes address and telephone directories, business cards and subscription, postal, and telephone rate lists
  - Public connections and support letters, 1993-1997. (Folder 11: 6-8)
    - Invitations, 1994-1997 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Letters in support of Russkaia mysl', 1993. (Folder 11: 7-8)
      Includes letters from Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Elena Bonner, Galina Starovoitova, and others
  - Card catalog of contributors, 1992-1996. (Folder 12)
    Includes one photographic slide depicting staff members of Russkaia mysl'
- Electronic documents, 1969-1972; 1 box (Box 13)
  Includes DVDs and CDs containing the log book of Arina Ginzburg, her correspondence with Aleksandr and other prisoners, and some individual documents and photographs. Also available on reading room workstation.
  - Correspondence between Aleksandr and Arina Ginzburg, 1969-1970. (Folder 13: 1)
    Includes one original postcard from Aleksandr to Arina, 1 DVD and 7 CDs. Use copies in the Hoover Archives reading room.
  - Logbook of Arina Ginzburg, 1969-1972. (Folder 13: 2-3)
    Includes 3 DVDs and 4 CDs with identical documents and some individual documents and photographs. Use copies in the Hoover Archives reading room
  - Selected documents and photographs printed out from CDs, 1969-1972 (Folder 13: 4-5)
- Photographs, 1950s-2002; 3 boxes (Box 14-16)
  Includes three groups of photographs: Aleksandr Ginzburg with his family and friends; his family members; and Ginzburg's friends and public figures.
  Arranged chronologically within each group
  - Aleksandr Ginzburg with family and friends, 1972-2002 (Envelope 14: 1-8)
    - 11 prints of Ginzburg, Aleksandr Ginzburg Jr., AlekseĬ Ginzburg, Giuzel' Amal'rik, EvgeniĬ IAkir, Kirill KostsinkiĬ, IuriĬ Orlov, ValeriĬ Ronkin, and Tat'iana Turchina, 1972-1977. (Envelope 14: 1)
    - 39 prints of Ginzburg, Vladimir BukovskiĬ, Mihajlo Mihajlov, Father Viktor Potapov, Maria Potapova, Mstislav Rostorpovch, Avital Shcharansky, Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn and Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna with their sons, and Lidiia Voronina, May-July 1979 (Envelope 14: 2)
    - 23 prints of Ginzburg's lecture tour in the United States, 1979-1980. (Envelope 14: 3)
    - 35 prints of Ginzburg, Petr Abovin-Egides, Mikhail Geller, Robert and Susan Massie, Kirill Pomernatsev, Maria Rozanova (Siniavski), Kira Sapgir, IuriĬ and A. Shikhanovich, Liudmila Soldatova, and others, 1980s. (Envelope 14: 4)
    - 27 prints of Aleksandr and Arina (Irina) Ginzburg, Petr Abovin-Egides, VasiliĬ Aksenov, IUriĬ Belov, VasiliĬ Betaki, Irina Delone, Mal'vina Dragosh, Irina El'konen, MaĬia Karmen, IUriĬ Mitiunov, Viktor Nekrasov, Bulat Okudzhava, Kirill Pomerantsev, Maria Rozanova (Siniavski), M. SlavinskiĬ, Irina Zaionchik, IUliia Voznesenskaia, and others, 1981-1983. (Envelope 14: 5)
    - 22 prints of Ginzburg, Irina Baskina, AndreĬ Bitov, Elena Bonner, Ol'ga IAkovleva, Fazil' Iskander, DmitriĬ Krymov, Natal'ia Krymova, Viktor Nekrasov, Bulat Okudzhava, AnatoliĬ Rybakov, SergeĬ and Tat'iana Khodorovich, AnatoliĬ Koriagin, AnatoliĬ Krasnov-Levitin, Igor' Vinogradov, Natal'ia Zelenko, 1987-1989. (Envelope 14: 6)
    - 39 prints of Ginzburg, Martina Audrie, Irina Bokova, Ambassador Mikhail Fedotov and Mariia Fedotova, Mikhail Gokhman, Eduard Grafov, Lidiia Grafova, Aleksandr IAkovlev, Vladimir KorsunskiĬ, SergeĬ Kaledin, Tat'iana Khodorovich, SergeĬ Kovalev, Mal'va Landa, Vera Lashkova, Alla Latynina, Leonid Latynin, IUriĬ Mitiunov, Bulat Okudzhava, ValeriĬ Prokhorov, AlekseĬ Simonov, Veniamin Smekhov, Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna, Vittorio Strada, Vladimir Vasil'ev, Oleg Volkov, Margarita Volkova, and members of the Russkaia mysl' editorial board, 1990-2000s. (Envelope 14: 7)
    - 10 prints of Ginzburg, ValeriĬ Abramkin, Efim Etkind, Vadim Nechaev, Maria Rozanova (Siniavski), IUliĬ Rybakov, Mikhail Sokolov, Viktor Suvorov and his wife, SergeĬ IUshenkov, ArkadiĬ Vaksberg, V. VishnevskiĬ, 2000-2002. (Envelope 14: 8)
  - Family members and friends, 1960s-1987 (Envelope 14: 9-10)
    - 47 prints of AlekseĬ and Aleksandr Ginzburg Jr, Liudmila Ginzburg (Aleksandr Ginzburg's mother), Vladlen Pavlenkov and Svetlana Pavlenkova, SergeĬ Shibaev, and others., 1960s-1970s. (Envelope 14: 9)
      Some photographs sent to Ginzburg in prison contain letters of Liudmila Ginzburg on the back
    - 36 prints of Ginzburg's sons AlekseĬ and Aleksandr, adopted son SergeĬ Shibaev, Liudmila Ginzburg, Vladimir AlloĬ, Ol'ga Burmistrova, Vera Bykova, IUliĬ Daniel', SergeĬ Dediulin, Irina Delone, Natal'ia Fedorova, Petr and Zinaida Grigorenko, Irina IlovaĬskaia, Tat'iana Khodorovich, Igor' Khokhlushkin, AlekseĬ Khvostenko, Mal'va Landa, Vera Lashkova, IUriĬ Mniukh, SergeĬ Moshkov, Viktor Nekrasov, Bulat Okudzhava, Irina Orlova, Aleksandr Podrabinek, ValeriĬ Prokhorov, Vladimir Rybakov, Kira Sapgir, Aleksandr Shuster, Viktor Timachev, Valentin Turchin, IUri Yarim-Agaev, Natal'ia Vladimova, Vladimir Voinovich, editors of the underground "Kolokol" magazine, and others, 1967-1987. (Envelope 14: 10)
  - Friends and public figures, 1950s-1995 and undated (Envelope 15: 1-8, 16: 1-6)
    - Includes 32 prints of Vadim Borisov, Ivan Kovalev, Aleksandr AĬkhenval'd, Zoia Krakhmal'nikova, AndreĬ Krasulin, Mikhail Makarenko, Filip Makhonin, Father Aleksandr Men' (including his rare pictures from the 1950s), Boris MikhaĬlov and Natal'ia MikhaĬlova and their children, Nadezhda Murina (Sarob'ianova), AnatoliĬ NaĬman, Viktor Nekrasov, Ida Nudel', Bulat Okudzhava, Irina Orlova (Valitova), IUriĬ Orlov, AlekseĬ Smirnov, Feliks Svetov, DmitriĬ ShakhovskoĬ, 1950s-1980s.; 1995. (Envelope 15: 1)
    - 48 prints of Vadim Borisov, Tat'iana Borisova, SergeĬ Khodorovich, Boris MikhaĬlov, Viktor Nekrasov, Bulat Okudzhava, Irina Orlova, EvgeniĬ Pasternak, Elena Pasternak, Elizaveta Pasternak, Vladlen Pavlenkov, Viktor Pavlenkov, Leonid Pliushch, Viacheslav Pochechuev, Mariia and Anastasiia Pod''iapol'skaia, GrigoriĬ Pod''iapol'skiĬ, Aleksandr Podrabinek with his family, VitaliĬ Pomazov, Kiril Pomerantsev, SergeĬ Ponomarev, Anna Prokof'eva, Viktor Timachev, GeorgiĬ Vladimov, and others; Press-conference commemorating anniversary of Ginzburg's arrest in 1977, 1960s-1980s. (Envelope 15: 2)
    - 25 prints of Liudmila Kovaleva, Aleksandr Orlov, IUliia Pessina, TanenboĬm, Liudmila Ternovskaia, Leonard TernovskiĬ, Petr Vail', Tat'iana Velikanova, GeorgiĬ Vladimov, Vladimir Vysotsky, Yuri Yarim-Agaev, Boris Yeltsin (during his first visit to France), IUliia Zaks, Vera Zelendinova, and others, 1960s-1991. (Envelope 15: 3)
    - 45 prints of Liudmila Alekseeva, Natal'ia Fedorova, Nina Gaenko, Sof'ia Kalistratova, Dina Kaminskaia, Irina Kaplun, SergeĬ Khodorovich, AlekseĬ Khvostenko, IUliĬ Kim, MaĬia Kopeleva, Vladimir KorsunskiĬ, Vera Kotan, Natal'ia Kravchneko, IUriĬ KublanovskiĬ, Eduard Kuznetsov, Mal'va and AlekseĬ Landa, Vera Lashkova, Aleksandr and Serafima Lavut, Pavel Litvinov, Tat'iana Litvinova with her daughter Mariia Slonim and grandson Anton Freidin-Slonim, Viktoriia Liubarskaia, Kronid LiubarskiĬ, Vladimir Maksimov, SergeĬ Moshkov, ArseniĬ RoginskiĬ, ValeriĬ Ronkin, AndreĬ Sakharov, IUriĬ Shikhanovich, Leonard TernovskiĬ, Viktor Timachev, IUliia Vishnevskaia, Aleksandr Zinov'ev, and others, Late 1960s-2000s. (Envelope 15: 4)
    - 36 prints of Elena Bonner, Tat'iana Borisova, Boris Delone, Venedikt Erofeev, Tat'iana Khromova, Alla Khromova (Podrabinek), Aleksandr Lavut, Natal'ia MikhaĬlova, Irina Orlova, Tat'iana Osipova, Aleksandr Podrabinek, Petr Starchik, Liudmila and Ol'ga Ternovskaia, Leonard TernovskiĬ, Viktor Timachev, Valentin Turchin, Tat'iana Turchina, Vladimir Tur'ianskiĬ, AndreĬ Tverdokhlebov. Court trials of Ginzburg, Orlov, and Shcharansky, 1970s. (Envelope 15: 5)
    - 39 prints of human right activists, presumably from Leningrad, 1970s. (Envelope 15: 6)
    - Includes 24 prints of EvgeniĬ Bachurin, Tat'iana Bakhmina and AndreĬ Bakmin with their children, Larisa Bogoraz, Elena Bonner, Vadim Borisov, Tat'iana Borisova, Joseph Brodsky, Nadezhda Bukharina, Vladimir BukovskiĬ, Irina IAkir, Vladimir Korner, Vladimir Maramzin, Valentin Turchin, Oleg Tselkov, and others, 1970s-1980s. (Envelope 15: 7)